A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Asia and Pacific, Office Files of Reuben Frodin FA553
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, International Division, Asia and Pacific, Office Files of Reuben Frodin
1966-1977
Rockefeller Archive Center
Frodin, Reuben
Ford Foundation
FA553
3 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
Alphabetical
Biographical / Historical
Reuben Frodin worked as a Program Advisor at the Ford Foundation for over ten years. Most of his time at the Foundation was spent in its International Division. At different times, he was a Program Advisor for Latin America and the Caribbean and Asia and the Pacific. He also had a position in the Division of Education and Research for a short period.
In addition to his work at the Ford Foundation, Frodin served as the Dean of the College of Liberal Arts and Sciences at the City University of New York (CUNY). He earned his doctorate and law degree from the University of Chicago.
Scope and Contents
Primarily contains meeting, committee, program and project planning records.
- Asia Meeting on Education Sessions 1-6, 1970 October (Box 1)
- Asia Meeting on Education Sessions 7-10, 1970 October (Box 1)
- Benson, Charles -- Education, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
- Bowman, Mary Jean, 1971 March 30 (Box 1)
- Callaway, Archibald, 1971 (Box 1)
- Caribbean -- Caribbean Textbook Project PA64-443, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
- Caribbean -- Institute of Education -- University of the West Indies (UWI) PA62-334, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
- Caribbean -- L69-169 Linguistics and Language Instruction in the Caribbean, 1969 (Box 1)
- Delhi University -- Review of Certain Grants of the Ford Foundation, 1975 March 31 (Box 1)
- Education "Alternatives", 1970-1971 (Box 1)
- Articles on Educational Planning, 1972 (Box 1)
- ID/HER Education Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
- ID/HER Education Group -- Seminar on Learning, 1977 (Box 1)
- Education Group -- Bellagio III, 1976 (Box 2)
- Education Group -- Sterling Forest Meeting, 1974 April 28-May 2 (Box 2)
- Education -- Miscellaneous Education Files, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
- Education -- Working File -- Resource Base Graduates (Box 2)
- Ford Foundation -- Education Television, 1973 (Box 2)
- Ford Foundation -- Language Studies, 1967-1971 (Box 2)
- Ford Foundation -- Language Development Study -- Background Papers, 1967 (Box 2)
- Indian Education in the 70s -- Howe/Gallagher, 1970 (Box 2)
- Indonesia -- Education Reports, 1975 (Box 2)
- Kidron, 1974 (Box 2)
- Law and Education, 1971 (Box 2)
- London School of Economics (Mark Blaug), 1971 (Box 2)
- Phillips, H.M. -- Various Reports, 1974 (Box 2)
- Population and Education, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
- Shaeffer, Sheldon -- Indonesian Education reports/preliminary dissertation, 1971-1977 (Box 2)
- University of the West Indies (UWI), 1966; Legal size. (Box 3)